Guide to the Chamberlain-Cravens-Cullinan family papers, 1900-2010 MS 594
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Chamberlain-Cravens-Cullinan family papers
1900-2010
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Chamberlain, Nancy Cravens (estate)
MS 594
70 Linear Feet (42 boxes + oversize materials)
The collection consists of correspondence, photographs, personal records, genealogy books, memorabilia, audio and visual materials, and ephemera collected by Nancy Cravens Chamberlain and representing the lives of her grandfather, Joseph Stephen Cullinan; her parents, Mary Cullinan and James R. Cravens; and herself and her siblings.
Biographical Note
The person who primarily preserved the items in this collection is Nancy Cravens Chamberlain, born in 1932 to Mary Cullinan and James Rorick Cravens. Mary Cullinan Cravens was one of five children born to Joseph Stephen Cullinan, founder of oil companies culminating with what became Texaco, early civic leader in Houston, and resident of the Shadyside development, one of the original houses being his.
J. S. Cullinan was born on December 31, 1860 near Sharon, Pennsylvania, the oldest son and second of eight children. Beginning to work in the Pennsylvania oilfields at the age of fourteen, he learned essentially every task associated with oil production. At the age of 22 he joined Standard Oil and held several management positions before leaving in 1895, at the age of 35, to form his own company, Petroleum Iron Works, which manufactured steel storage tanks.
When oil was discovered in Corsicana, Texas, in 1894, Cullinan was sought out for advice on production and marketing techniques. In Corsicana he formed a company in his own name, which later became the Magnolia Petroleum Company. Cullinan was instrumental in introducing oil as a fuel for locomotives, the use of natural gas for heating and lighting, and using oil to settle dust on streets. In 1899 he constructed a refinery south of Corsicana, the first such facility west of the Mississippi. Also in 1899 he had an important role in persuading the Texas legislature to enact the state's first statute for petroleum conservation.
Shortly after the Spindletop discovery in 1901 Cullinan moved to Beaumont, where he founded the Texas Company (later Texaco). In 1905 he moved the Texaco headquarters to Houston. Losing his controlling interest of Texaco stock in a proxy fight with eastern investors in 1913, Cullinan resigned as president but remained active in the industry. He was instrumental in developing the Sour Lake, Humble, and East Texas oilfields.
From 1913 to 1919 Cullinan served as president of the Houston Chamber of Commerce and supported development of the Houston Ship Channel. In 1922 he was responsible for construction of the North Side Belt Railway around the city. He served as special advisor to the Food Administration under Herbert Hoover during World War I. Beneficiaries of his philanthropy were the Museum of Fine Arts, the Houston Symphony Orchestra, and the Houston Negro Hospital. He served as chairman of the Mount Rushmore National Memorial Committee from 1928 to 1933. In 1937 while visiting his friend Herbert Hoover in Palo Alto, California, Cullinan died of pneumonia on March 11.
Members of three generations are represented in this collection: Nancy's grandfather's, J. S. Cullinan's; her parents', the Cravens'; and the generation of Nancy and her siblings, Anne, James "Chico," and Patsy Cravens. Nancy was married to Charles Devere Chamberlain, Jr. from 1954 to 1974. The span of time represented in the collection is 1907 to 2003. Nancy Cravens Chamberlain died in 2010.
As the eldest surviving child of Mary and James Cravens, Nancy was the preserver of records, photographs, and memorabilia from the two preceding generations as well as her own. In addition to, effectively, being family historian, Nancy earned a bachelor's degree in 1975 and a master's in English in 1980 from the University of Houston. She became known for generous volunteer work teaching adult literacy classes for ten years. She also tutored children at Gregory Lincoln Elementary School and counseled alcoholics and drug addicts.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of correspondence, personal records, photographs, genealogy books, e-mails, audio and visual materials, other books, memorabilia, and ephemera. Three generations are represented, particularly in the correspondence and photographs. The extensive correspondence portion is made up of letters of family members, friends, and business associates. Personal records include estate documents of various family members. Also included are business correspondence and publications about J. S. Cullinan's several oil companies, as well as material related to James Rorick Cravens and Cravens, Dargan, and Company. The photographs are comprised of both family photographs at home and pictures taken in various vacation settings in both the U.S. and abroad.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was received from the estate of Nancy Cravens Chamberlain December 23, 2011.
Related Materials
Chamberlain Genealogy Book Collection housed separately at the Woodson Research Center
Joseph S. Cullinan Papers, 1893-1939, ID: 07/2006-009, Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Index Terms
Subjects
Petroleum industry and trade; Social life and customs
Document Types
photographs; scrapbooks; diaries; letters (correspondence); genealogies (histories)
Places
Houston (Tex.) -- History.
Subjects (Persons)
Cullinan, J. S. (Joseph Stephen)
- Series I: Correspondence, 173567
  - Subseries A: Family, 173573
    - James Arcidiacono, 1979-1981; 173592 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Johnny Arcidiacono, 1974-1980; 173593 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Joseph Arcidiacono, 1980; 173594 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Peter Arcidiacono, 1976-1978; 173595 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Anne Chamberlain, 1951-1986; 173596 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Anne Chamberlain, 1987-1993; 173597 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Charles Chamberlain, 1934-1977; 173598 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Charles Chamberlain III, 1971-1983; 173599 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Charles Chamberlain III, 1984-1991; 173600 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Laura Chamberlain, 1968-1992; 173601 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Mary Chamberlain, 1964-1990; 173602 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Mary Chamberlain, undated; 173603 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Nancy Cravens Chamberlain childhood letters and ephemera, 1932-1941; 173604 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Nancy Cravens Chamberlain, 1942-1945; 173605 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Nancy Cravens Chamberlain, 1946-1947; 173606 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Nancy Cravens Chamberlain, 1948; 173607 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Nancy Cravens Chamberlain, 1949; 173608 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Nancy Cravens Chamberlain, 1950; 173609 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Nancy Cravens Chamberlain, 1951; 173610 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Nancy Cravens Chamberlain, 1952; 173611 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Nancy Cravens Chamberlain, 1953-1954; 173612 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Nancy Cravens Chamberlain, 1955; 173613 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Nancy Cravens Chamberlain, 1956-1957; 173614 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Nancy Cravens Chamberlain, 1958-1965; 173615 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Nancy Cravens Chamberlain, 1966-1969; 173616 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Nancy Cravens Chamberlain, 1970-1975; 173617 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Nancy Cravens Chamberlain, 1976-1978; 173618 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Nancy Cravens Chamberlain, 2001, undated; 173619 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - The Chamberlains (Charles' parents), 1957; 173620 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Detta and Martha Considine, 1920-1930; 173621 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Jane Considine, 1932; 173622 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Mr. and Mrs. John Considine, 1928-1971; 173623 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Augusta Donna Ferguson Cravens, 1929-1937; 173624 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Augusta Donna Ferguson Cravens, 1938-1948, undated; 173625 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Clay Cravens, 1975-1980; 173626 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - James Cravens, 1907-1935; 173627 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - James Rorick Cravens, 1902-1949; 173628 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - James Rorick Cravens, 1950-1959; 173629 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - James Rorick Cravens, 1960-1977, undated; 173630 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - James "Chico" Cravens, Jr., 1944-1997; 173631 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Kay Cravens, 1967; 173632 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Malcolm Cravens, 1929-1994; 173633 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Mary Catherine Cullinan Cravens, 1911-1927; 173634 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Mary Catherine Cullinan Cravens, 1928-1929; 173635 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Mary Catherine Cullinan Cravens, 1930-1974; 173636 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Mary Catherine Cullinan Cravens, 1975-1985, undated; 173637 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Patsy Cravens, 1944-1979; 173638 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Will Cravens, 1975-1977; 173639 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - The Cullinans, 1930-1935; 173640 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Anna Cullinan, 1898-1954; 173641 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Barbara Cullinan, 1936-1976; 173642 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Barrie Cullinan, 1975-1976; 173643 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Craig Cullinan, 1911-1949; 173644 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Craig Cullinan, Jr., 1935-1983; 173645 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Edith Cullinan, 1930-1948; 173646 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Eustace Cullinan, 1930; 173647 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Frank Cullinan, 1918; 173648 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Harvey J. Cullinan, 1934; 173649 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - John Halm Cullinan, 1912-1917; 173650 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - J.S. Cullinan, 1890s; 173651 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - J.S. Cullinan, 1900-1904; 173652 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - J.S. Cullinan, 1905-1909; 173653 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - J.S. Cullinan, 1910-1914; 173654 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - J.S. Cullinan, 1915-1919; 173655 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - J.S. Cullinan, 1920-1922; 173656 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - J.S. Cullinan, 1923-1925; 173657 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - J.S. Cullinan, 1926-1928; 173658 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - J.S. Cullinan, 1929-1930; 173659 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - J.S. Cullinan, 1931-1932; 173660 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - J.S. Cullinan, 1933-1934; 173661 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - J.S. Cullinan, 1935; 173662 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - J.S. Cullinan, 1936-1937; 173663 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - J.S. Cullinan, undated; 173664 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Joseph Cullinan II, 1944-1983; 173665 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Joseph Cullinan III, 1983; 173666 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Lucie Halm Cullinan, 1898-1917; 173667 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Lucie Halm Cullinan, 1918-1928, undated; 173668 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - McAfee Cullinan, 1934-1958; 173669 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Nina Jane Cullinan, 1916-1992, undated; 173670 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Sue Cullinan, 1983; 173671 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Willie Cullinan, 1931; 173672 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Helen Ferguson, 1929-1959; 173673 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Mary Halm, 1891-1893; 173674 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Michael Halm, 1899; 173675 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - W.E. Halm, 1924-1925; 173676 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Anderson Todd, 1977; 173677 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - David Anderson Todd, 1969-1980; 173678 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Emily Leland Todd, 1965-1976; 173679 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Lucie Wray Todd, 1942-1985; 173680 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - A.J. Wray, 1931-1976; 173681 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Margaret Cullinan Wray, 1898-1928; 173682 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Margaret Cullinan Wray, 1929-1942; 173683 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Margaret Cullinan Wray, 1943-1947; 173684 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Margaret Cullinan Wray, 1948-1994; 173685 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Margaret Cullinan Wray, undated; 173686 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Subseries B: Friends and Associates, 173574
    - Irmgard V.R. Alexander, 1930-1931; 173687 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Landon and Charlean Alexander, 1976; 173688 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Palmer Archer, 1934; 173689 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Ike Ashburn, 1943; 173690 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Autry Family, 1904-1976; 173691 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence-A, 1924-1994; 173692 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Dori Babyak, 1985-1987; 173693 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Adelaide Baker, 1929-1976; 173694 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Edgar J. Banks, 1935; 173695 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - E.C. Barkley, 1929; 173696 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Cupe Black, 1935; 173697 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - E. Bolle, 1974; 173698 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Mrs. B.F. Bonner, 1933; 173699 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Gutzon and Mary Borglum, 1929-1936; 173700 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - H.I. Brady, 1931; 173701 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Tucker Bremen, 1933-1935; 173702 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Marjory Bridge, 1932-1938; 173703 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Debbie Brown, 1974-1975; 173704 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - T.E. Buchanan, 1926-1928; 173705 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - General Correspondence- B, 1919-2001; 173706 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Richard Campbell, 1928-1935; 173707 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Eloise Helbig Chalmera, 1929-1958; 173708 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Ralph Cole, 1978; 173709 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Calvin Coolidge, 1930; 173710 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - William T. Cosgrave, 1930-1935; 173711 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Carey Croneis, 1969; 173712 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Leo St. Cyr, 1935; 173713 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - General Correspondence-C, 1921-1992; 173714 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - E.H. Daly, 1959; 173715 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Helen Dann, 1975; 173716 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Helen Denby, 1923-1929; 173717 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - The Diehls, 1949; 173718 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Hugh Durbin, 1983-1984; 173719 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - James Durbin, 1931; 173720 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - General Correspondence-D, 1922-1994; 173721 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Joe H. Eagle, 1928-1933; 173722 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Betsy Eames, 1929-1967; 173723 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Virginia Elder, 1954-1955; 173724 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - General Correspondence-E, 1968-1994; 173725 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Karin Fagerburg, 1948-1950; 173726 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Ed Feeney, 1928; 173727 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Frank C. Flanagan, 1922-1928; 173728 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Mary Frances, 1920-1931; 173729 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Carolyn Wilford Fuqua, 1985; 173730 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - General Correspondence-F, 1887-1967; 173731 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Chaille Thompson Gale, 1976-1990; 173732 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Mary Garden, 1930-1934; 173733 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Eula Garrison, 1918-1934; 173734 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Duane V. Geis, 1994; 173735 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Oliver St. J. Gogarty, 1930; 173736 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Jolie Golumb, 1974-1975; 173737 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - J.E. Gorman, 1928-1934; 173738 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Joseph F. Guffey, 1928-1930; 173739 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - General Correspondence-G, 1903-1994; 173740 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Louise Closser Hale, 1930; 173741 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Ross Harris, 1975; 173742 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Will Hogg, 1912-1914; 173743 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Virginia H. Holt, 1947-1948; 173744 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Eleanor E. Hondias, 1924; 173745 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Roy A. Howard, 1931-1934; 173746 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Dorothea Hugel, 1947-1949; 173747 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - General Correspondence-H, 1922-1994; 173748 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - General Correspondence-I, 1935; 173749 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Virginia Jago, 1939-1955; 173750 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - General Correspondence-J, 1922-1984; 173751 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Chaille Cage Kelly, 1929-1994; 173752 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - E.J. Kyle, 1930-1931; 173753 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - General Correspondence-K, 1929-1983; 173754 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Marion Law, 1926-1977; 173755 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Mary Loudon, 1934-1939; 173756 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - The Lovetts, 1928-1969; 173757 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Frank O. Lowden, 1930-1931; 173758 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - General Correspondence-L, 1930-1990; 173759 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Lee Malone, 1958; 173760 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Gene Markery, 1923; 173761 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Watt R. Matthews, 1929; 173762 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - T.J. McMillan, 1933-1934; 173763 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Nanette Mengel, 1950; 173764 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Bunny Meyers, 1973-1975; 173765 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Emma Guffey Miller, 1933-1935; 173766 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Roy Miller, 1934; 173767 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Frances D. Misfeldt, 1948-1949; 173768 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Betty B. Mitchell, 1934; 173769 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - W.W. Moore, 1928-1930; 173770 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - George R. Morgan, 1943-1971; 173771 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - E.E. Morrison, 1920-1921; 173772 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - W.G. Morrison, 1921; 173773 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - General Correspondence-M, 1895-1994; 173774 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Hugo Neuhaus, Jr., 1958; 173775 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Midshipman R.G. Neville, 1950; 173776 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - General Correspondence-N, 1929; 173777 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Eugenie Osi, 1898-1936; 173778 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - General Correspondence-O, 1928-1983; 173779 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Ethel Parks, 1975-1994; 173780 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - R.E. Powell, 1931-1938; 173781 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - General Correspondence-P, 1891-1936; 173782 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - General Correspondence-Q, 1920; 173783 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - Eliya Randall, 1952-1954; 173784 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Francine Randolph, 1928-1940; 173785 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Mary Reed, 1975; 173786 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Karl Reiland, 1930-1931; 173787 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Ruth Rieber, 1958-1971; 173788 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - T. Rieber, 1935-1966; 173789 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Florence Rogers, 1933; 173790 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Rundle Family (Austria), undated; 173791 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - George W. Russell, 1923-1935; 173792 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - General Correspondence-R, 1928-1985; 173793 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Richard F. Sawyer, 1928-1971; 173794 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Ruth Sawyer, 1958-1982; 173795 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Schmitt Family, 1947-1950; 173796 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Pete Schweppe, 1994; 173797 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Mrs. W.A. Scott, 1956; 173798 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - David C. Seager, 1977; 173799 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Estelle Sharp, 1929; 173800 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - R.A. Shepherd, 1927-1930; 173801 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - E.P. Sine, 1931; 173802 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Lucy A. Singleton, 1950; 173803 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Daniel S. Slawson, 1945; 173804 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Anne Staley, 1976; 173805 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Walter Starkie, 1957-1959; 173806 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Vilhjalmur Stefansson, 1922-1930; 173807 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Henry Stude, Jr., 1940-1946; 173808 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Henry Stude, 1933-1945; 173809 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Jane Stude, 1916-1973; 173810 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - General Correspondence-S, 1887-1994; 173811 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - General Correspondence-T, 1928-1994; 173812 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - General Correspondence-U, 1975-1979; 173813 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Vladimir Vaiecha, 1989-1992; 173814 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Frank E. Vandiver, 1969-1970; 173815 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - General Correspondence-V, 1936-1968; 173816 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - John Walsh, 1933; 173817 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Marge Wilford, 1972-1976; 173818 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - William Williamson, 1930; 173819 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Mildred Meador Wilson, 1960-1961; 173820 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - William A. Wilson, 1922; 173821 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - J.E. Wooding, 1930-1931; 173822 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - General Correspondence-W, 1923-1996; 173823 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Martha Youngblood, 1985-1986; 173824 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - General Correspondence-Y, undated; 173825 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - C.M. Zimmer, 1934-1935; 173826 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - General Correspondence-Z, 1985; 173827 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Agnes, 1930; 173828 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - General Correspondence, First Name A-D, 1892-1994; 173829 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Ed and Sally, 1926-1959; 173830 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - General Correspondence, First Name E-J, 1909-1997; 173831 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Katy Ruth, 1914-1929; 173832 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Loo/Roo, 1932-1999; 173833 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - General Correspondence, First Name K-O, 1912-1994; 173834 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - General Correspondence, First Name P-Z, 1923-1990; 173835 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Various German Correspondents (WWII era), 173836 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Subseries C: Businesses and Organizations, 173575
    - Fidelity Trust Company, 1915-1920; 173837 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Fidelity Trust Company, 1921-1924; 173838 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Fidelity Trust Company, 1925-1928; 173839 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Fidelity Trust Company, 1929-1932; 173840 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Fidelity Trust Company, 1933-1936; 173841 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Fidelity Trust Company, 1937-1945; 173842 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Glenwood Cemetery, 1977-1997; 173843 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Harris County Afro-American Medical Association, 1929; 173844 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Houston Parks Board, 1981-1993; 173845 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Junior League, 1929-1994; 173846 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - L.W. Stolz Memorials, 1976-1977; 173847 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Museum of Fine Arts Houston, 1928-1965; 173848 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Navarro County Historical Society, 1977-1979; 173849 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Petroleum Protective Association, Inc., 1925-1927; 173850 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - veterans' Affairs, 1976; 173851 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - W.M. Egan and Sons LTD, 1930; 173852 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Houston Organizations, 1928-1994; 173853 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Non-Houston Organizations, 1927-1979; 173854 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Subseries D: Children's Notes and Ephemera, 173576
    - Drawings, 173855 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - School Projects, 173856 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Medical Reports for Nancy, Patsy, and Chico, 173857 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Notes from Kids, 173858 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Paper Dolls, 1910-1911; 173859 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Reports from Camp, 173860 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Subseries E: School Records, 173577
    - Chatham Hall: General, 173861 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Chatham Hall: Alumni Publications, 173862 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Chihuahuan Desert Research Institute, 173863 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Hollins College, 173864 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Lewis and Clark College, 173865 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Smith College: Events, 173866 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Smith College: Records, 173867 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Smith College: Reunions, 173868 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Smith College: Schoolwork, 1921-1923; 173869 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - St. Stephen's Episcopal School, 173870 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - University of Houston, 173871 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous School Records, 173872 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Subseries F: Births, Marriages, and Deaths, 173578
      - Flower Cards from Lucie Halm Cullinan's death, 1927; 173873 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Sympathy Cards regarding the death of James Cravens, Sr., 1936-1937; 173874 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Sympathy Letters regarding the death of J.S. Cullinan, 1937; 173875 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Telegrams regarding the death of J.S. Cullinan, 1937; 173876 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - Sympathy Letters regarding Donna Cravens' death, 1951; 173877 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Sympathy Letters regarding Rorick Cravens' death (1 of 2), 1976; 173878 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Sympathy Letters regarding Rorick Cravens' death (2 of 2), 1976; 173879 (Box 6, Folder 25)